# Ahmed Mamdouh

Senior Full Stack-Engineer | Github - LinkedIn - My Website

(+02) 01111 98 1716 gm.xerk@gmail.com

Address: Giza, Haram, Egypt

#### **SUMMARY:**

I am a Software Engineer with 6+ years of experience in both front-end and back-end development. I developed many websites, web apps, integrated many API payment systems. I worked also with PHP, Laravel, NestJS, Nodejs, ReactJS. Created many eCommerce websites, LMS, SMS, SaaS. Developed many payment systems and also started APIs from scratch, Projects.

#### **EXPERIENCE:**

## Netsync — Senior Software Engineer (US)

Feb 2023 - Present (go2alto.com, Netsync.io)

- Led a high-performing team of full-stack engineers skilled in Laravel and Angular
- Manage Jira and tasks
- Manage servers and handle pipeline CI/CD
- Managed end-to-end software development lifecycle

# SweepSouth — Senior Software Engineer (South Africa)

Apr 2022 - Feb 2023 (FilKedma, SweepSouth)

- Develop and launch applications by using "Laravel" for the back-end and "Angular.js" for the front-end & MongoDB as NoSQL Database.
- Drove server-side development with expertise in JavaScript and Node.js, ensuring the scalability and performance of critical systems.
- Utilized Vue.js and ElectronJS to create modern and userfriendly front-end interfaces.
- Orchestrated containerization and deployment using Kubernetes and Docker, optimizing resource management and deployment efficiency.
- Deployment & maintenance server using AWS

# Technocloud — Sneior Team Lead

Aug 2020 – Apr 2022 (Zerocash App, Zerocash, Rojetah, Dealmart App, Trjim)

- Develop and launch applications by using "Laravel" for the back-end and "Vue.js" for the front-end.
- Successfully introduced Agile to design and development teams comprising over 7 employees.
- Updated agile tracking systems to provide transparency on product & sprint backlogs streamlining communication and reducing support requests.
- Develops new and maintains existing applications
- Deployment & maintenance server using (Laravel forge & ssh)

### **SKILLS: LANGUAGES:**

PHP JavaScript

#### FRAMEWORKS:

Laravel Vue.js.

Node.js React.js

Electron Codelgniter

SCSS/SASS/LESS Tailwindcss

Bootstrap. AngularJS

## Database:

MySQL MSSQL MongoDB Postgres

## OTHER SKILLS:

## Linux/Windows/MacOS

ES6+ UI / UX
AdobeXD CI/CD
GitHub Agile
Clickup Asana
Deployment Server (DevOps)
MVC HMVC

Repository pattern

Services pattern GraphQL

## Integrations:

Paymob InstaPay
Stripe Slack
Datasets LinkedIn

Facebook Google(GMT, etc)

0Auth Foodics

Fawry Nexmo & Twilio SMS

### Tools:

Laravel Nova Laravel Cashier

All Laravel Tools Jenkins
FilamentPHP Laravel Forge

Vue Router Vuex

# Itrinity — Senior Software Engineer (Slovakia)

Oct 2019 - Aug 2020 (Uptimerobot)

- Led development with Node.js, NestJS, and GraphQL to create robust back-end systems and APIs.
- Demonstrated expertise in PHP development, utilizing CakePHP and Laravel for web application development.
- Worked with RESTful APIs to facilitate data exchange and communication between services.
- Deployment & maintenance server using AWS
- Utilized Notion for efficient software management, ensuring project workflows and tasks were well-organized.

# Schoolver — Software Engineer

Mar 2017- Oct 2019 (schoolver.com)

- Development application by using "Laravel" & "Vue.js"
- Develop and launch applications by using "Laravel" for the back-end and "Vue js" for the front-end.
- Using CI/CD for launch applications and new features.
- Shipping software by using the agile methodology.
- Build SMS & LMS for schools

#### Responsibilities:

- Setting a vision for how technology will be used in the company.
- Ensuring that technological resources meet the company's short and long-term needs.
- Outline the goals for research and development.
- Creating timelines for the development and deployment of all technological services.
- Making executive decisions on behalf of the company's technological requirements.
- Acting as a mentor to team members.
- Maintaining a consumer-focused outlook and aiding in the delivery of IT projects to market.
- Managing technology budgets and time frames.
- Staying on top of technology trends and developments.
- Ensuring all technology practices adhere to regulatory standards.

## **EDUCATION:**

# Akhbar El Youm Academy — Bachelor's degree

2014- 2018 – Computer Science

#### **PROJECTS:**

- Go2alto: Device management IPTV, Build with (Laravel, mongodb, Socket.io, Nodejs, restful API)
- Laranj: POS system Restaurant and merchant, Build with (Laravel, Vuejs, MySQL, GraphQL)
- Ahmed Mamdouh Software Engineer (xerk.io): My Website and my information (ReactJS, NextJS)
- Home Services Made Easy | Egypt | Filkhedma: FilKhedma is a Home Services (Lumen and Angular 5, MongoDB)
- Cleaning Services | Hire a Cleaner | 087 711 0573 | SweepSouth: Cleaning Home Services in South Africa
- App Zerocash, Zerocash App: (E-wallet application secure money management app, allow you to make purchases with merhcants, transfer or send money, etc..)

## Laravel & Vuejs & restful API & MySQL

- Rojetah, Rojetah App: Healthcare Ecosyste, Build with (Codeigniter PHP, MySQL, restful API)
- Dealmart App: (E-commerce software with lottery system, Build with (Laravel, restful API, MySQL)
- <u>Trjim:</u> (Trjim is middleware between translator and agency, build with (Laravel)

- Gulftic: (CRM website but isn't work now build with (Laravel, NuxtJS)
- Prooflo: (Prooflo is management tool like Jira and Asana I build using (Laravel, Vuejs)
- <u>UptimeRobot: Free Website Monitoring Service</u> (Microservices, PHP, JS, NodeJS, React, Vuejs,.. etc)
- Multy App (xerk.io): (Nuxt 3, Backend Laravel, Nova, TailwindCSS)
- Mall Of Arabia (xerk.io) (The Biggest Mall in Egypt, NuxtJS 3, TailwindCSS, from XD Design)
- <u>Sinbad Now</u>: (Multi vendor for Shipping Companies & Shops & using multi <u>Tenancy for Laravel</u>, Laravel, Vuejs)
- eduvaly, schoolver, Masknow
- GitHub (public task projects Laravel, Vue.JS, FilamentPHP (Bus Ticket), My GitHub 44 public and private Repos